# 虽然说听粉蒸肉的名字已经很久了
Although I've heard about Fenzhengrou ("Flour Steamed Meat") for long
# 但是尝它的味道还是头一次
But this is my first time to taste it
# 还是满心的期待呀
And I’m really looking forward to it
# 陕西 西安
Xi’an, Shaanxi
# 我要个大份的（粉蒸肉）带走
I want a large (fenzhengrou) to go
# 大份多少钱
How much?
# 23元
23 yuan
# 这是粉蒸肉的精华-肥油
This is the essence of fenzhengrou - fatty tallow
# 这一盆的牛肉 切的都是这么大块的
All beef in the pot were chopped into big pieces
# 这开始加入调味的料汁了
They start adding seasoning sauce
# 这个粉蒸肉是用面粉做的
Their fenzhengrou is made with wheat flour
# 有的地方使用米粉做的
It's made with rice flour at some other places
# （用的粉是不同点）
Different flour
# 搅拌均匀 然后就可以准备上笼了
Stir well and ready to put on the steamer
# 现在是盖了一层的肥肉
They've laid a layer of fatty meat
# 蒸熟后 口感会更加滑润 味道会更香
After steaming, the taste will be smoother and more fragrant
# 现在是六笼 待会蒸2个小时就可以吃了
Now there are six steamers of steamed meat. They will be ready to serve after two hours
# 这个粉蒸肉就是传统的 西安回坊的宵夜食品
This fenzhengrou is a traditional night street food in Huifang, Xi'an
# 以前售卖时候 把灯点亮了才卖这个东西（天黑时候）
They used to sell it when the light was on (after dark)
# 咱这叫西安回坊的宵夜
Let's call it Xi'an Huifang's midnight food
# 特色就在这个点上
This is the special thing
# 这个粉蒸肉的油份比较大
This fenzhengrou is rich in oil
# 喝茶的好处是一个是解油腻 一个是便于消化
The benefit of drinking tea is that it reduces the grease and helps digestion
# 一口茶 一口肉 一口蒜
A sip of tea, a bite of meat, a bite of garlic
# 吃着具有一种独特的味道
which give you a unique taste
# 2小时后
Two hours later
# 你好
hi
# 坐下来了 发现了蒜
We sat down and found garlic
# 我们的粉蒸肉已经上来了
Our fenzhengrou is on the table
# 麽麽哒（没问题）
No problem
# 我确实得先喝点了 真的是太渴了
I need to drink something first because I am so thirsty
# 天气太热了
The weather is too hot
# 茶 蒜 粉蒸肉每一个单拿出来都是一种味道
Tea, garlic, steamed meat, every single one has a distinct taste
# 但是把3个配在一起吃 还是第一次尝试
However, it’s my first time to eat them together
# 先尝尝单个的味道
Let’s taste each of them first
# 刚吃大叔说 粉蒸肉的面比肉好吃 先来一口
Just heard the uncle say that the flour in the fenzhengrou tastes better than the meat. Let me try
# 真的是这个面已经把牛肉和调料的味道都吸收进来了
The flour has absorbed the taste of beef and seasoning
# 来口蒜吧
Let me have a bite of garlic
# 这个肥肉真是一抿就化啊
This fatty meat melts in a sip
# 我的蒜呢
Where is my garlic?
# 第一次对蒜这么情有独钟
I love garlic that much for the first time
# 嘴上有种麻麻的感觉 让你越吃越想吃
There is a feeling of numbness in my mouth, making you want to eat more
# 吃粉蒸肉不仅可以白口吃
You can eat fenzhengrou alone
# 还可以夹在荷叶饼里来吃
You can also eat it in a "heyebing" flatbread
# 顾客：多给点面吧
Customer: "may I have more flour?"
# 我喜欢吃这个面
I like the flour
# 给点肥的要不要
How about some fatty?
# 来点吧
okay
# 吃得满足了
I'm satisfied
# 也告别了可爱的小姐姐
Also said goodbye to the lovely young lady
# 今天的视频就到这 拜拜
That's all for today’s video, bye